{
	"questions": [

		{
			"question": "Click on the first planet.",
			"fact": "<start>",
			"answers": ["mercury"],
			"live": true
		},

		{
			"question": "Click on the second planet.",
			"fact": "<start>",
			"answers": ["venus"],
			"live": true
		},

		{
			"question": "Click on the third planet.",
			"fact": "<start>",
			"answers": ["earth"],
			"live": true
		},

		{
			"question": "Click on the 4th planet.",
			"fact": "<start>",
			"answers": ["mars"],
			"live": true
		},

		{
			"question": "Click on the 5th planet.",
			"fact": "<start>",
			"answers": ["jupiter"],
			"live": true
		},

		{
			"question": "Click on the 6th planet.",
			"fact": "<start>",
			"answers": ["saturn"],
			"live": true
		},

		{
			"question": "Click on the 7th planet.",
			"fact": "<start>",
			"answers": ["uranus"],
			"live": true
		},

		{
			"question": "Click on 8th planet.",
			"fact": "<start>",
			"answers": ["neptune"],
			"live": true
		},












		{
			"question": "Click on Mercury",
			"fact": "This is Mercury. It is the closest planet to the sun.",
			"answers": ["mercury"],
			"live": false
		},

		{
			"question": "Click on Venus",
			"fact": "This is Venus. It is the 2nd planet from the sun.",
			"answers": ["venus"],
			"live": false
		},

		{
			"question": "Click on Earth",
			"fact": "This is Earth. We are the 3rd planet from the sun.",
			"answers": ["earth"],
			"live": false
		},

		{
			"question": "Click on Mars",
			"fact": "This is Mars. It is the 4th planet from the sun.",
			"answers": ["mars"],
			"live": false
		},

		{
			"question": "Click on Jupiter",
			"fact": "This is Jupiter. It is the 5th planet from the sun.",
			"answers": ["jupiter"],
			"live": false
		},

		{
			"question": "Click on Saturn",
			"fact": "This is Saturn. It is the 6th planet from the sun.",
			"answers": ["saturn"],
			"live": false
		},

		{
			"question": "Click on Uranus",
			"fact": "This is Uranus. It is the 7th planet from the sun.",
			"answers": ["uranus"],
			"live": false
		},

		{
			"question": "Click on Neptune",
			"fact": "This is Neptune. It is the 8th (and furthest) planet from the sun.",
			"answers": ["neptune"],
			"live": false
		},











		{
			"question": "Which planet has life (that we know of)?",
			"fact": "Earth is the only planet with life on it (that we know of).",
			"answers": ["earth"],
			"live": false
		},

		{
			"question": "Which planets have no rings",
			"fact": "Mercury, Venus, Earth, Mars, and Jupiter have no visible rings.",
			"answers": ["mercury", "venus", "earth", "mars", "jupiter"],
			"live": false
		},

		{
			"question": "Which planets have rings",
			"fact": "Saturn, Uranus, Neptune have rings",
			"answers": ["saturn", "uranus", "neptune"],
			"live": false
		},

		{
			"question": "Which planet has no moons?",
			"fact": "Mercury and Venus have no moons.",
			"answers": ["mercury", "venus"],
			"live": false
		},

		{
			"question": "Which planet has no atmosphere?",
			"fact": "Mercury has no atmosphere (air).",
			"answers": ["mercury"],
			"live": false
		},

		{
			"question": "What is the biggest planet in out solar system?",
			"fact": "Jupiter is the biggest planet in our solar system.",
			"answers": ["jupiter"],
			"live": false
		},

		{
			"question": "What is the smallest planet in out solar system?",
			"fact": "Mercury is the smallest planet in our solar system.",
			"answers": ["mercury"],
			"live": false
		},

		{
			"question": "Which planets are gas giants?",
			"fact": "Jupiter, Saturn, Uranus and Neptune are known as gas giants because they are made of gas.",
			"answers": ["jupiter", "saturn", "uranus", "neptune"],
			"live": false
		},

		{
			"question": "Which planets have a solid surface (terrestrial)?",
			"fact": "Mercury, Venus, Earth and Mars have solid surfaces (they are \"terrestrial\").",
			"answers": ["mercury", "venus", "earth", "mars"],
			"live": false
		},

		{
			"question": "Which planet has a molten metal core?",
			"fact": "Mercury, Earth and Mars have molten metal cores.",
			"answers": ["mercury", "earth", "mars"],
			"live": false
		},

		{
			"question": "Which planet is an ice giant (has an ice core)?",
			"fact": "Uranus and Neptune are known as ice giants because there cores are made of ice",
			"answers": ["uranus", "neptune"],
			"live": false
		},









		{
			"question": "Which planet spins backwards?",
			"fact": "Venus and Uranus spin backwards. The sun rises in the west, and sets in the east.",
			"answers": ["venus", "uranus"],
			"live": false
		},

		{
			"question": "Which planet rotates sideways?",
			"fact": "Uranus rotates on its side.",
			"answers": ["uranus"],
			"live": false
		},

		{
			"question": "What is the windiest planet?",
			"fact": "Neptune is the windiest planet, where wind speeds can reach 2,000 kilometers per hour.",
			"answers": ["neptune"],
			"live": false
		},

		{
			"question": "Which planet gets its color from iron minerals rusting (oxidizing)?",
			"fact": "Mars is red because iron mineral on the surface are rusting (oxidizing).",
			"answers": ["mars"],
			"live": false
		},

		{
			"question": "Which planet has two moons called Phobos and Deimos?",
			"fact": "Mars has two moons called Phobos and Deimos.",
			"answers": ["mars"],
			"live": false
		},

		{
			"question": "Which planet has a red spot that is a giant storm?",
			"fact": "The red spot on Jupiter is a giant storm.",
			"answers": ["jupiter"],
			"live": false
		},

		{
			"question": "Which planet has 67 moons?",
			"fact": "Juptier has 67 known moons, the most out of all the planets.",
			"answers": ["jupiter"],
			"live": false
		},

		{
			"question": "Which planet has 62 moons?",
			"fact": "Saturn has 62 moons.",
			"answers": ["saturn"],
			"live": false
		},

		{
			"question": "Which planet is made of mostly hydrogen and helium?",
			"fact": "The gas giants (Jupiter, Saturn, Uranus and Neptune) are mostly made of hydrogen and helium gas.",
			"answers": ["jupiter", "saturn", "uranus", "neptune"],
			"live": false
		},

		{
			"question": "Which gas planet is also made of water, ammonia and methane?",
			"fact": "The ice giants (Uranus and Neptune) are mostly made of water, ammonia and methane.",
			"answers": ["uranus", "neptune"],
			"live": false
		}


	]
}
